<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Love Huria - Drupal, Javascript, Web</title>
    <description>A blog site about anything related to web.</description>
    <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lhuria94.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 14:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 14:11:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is IAM? (A beginner's guide)</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ah, it feels good to be back into blogging days 🤩. So, a little bit about what I’m up to these days; I am currently engaged in helping build an identity and access management solution for one of the projects. Now in IAM, there are a lot of things to cover but we will focus on the basics of it. While working on this piece, I have realized that the core concepts are often a gap in understanding with respect to what it actually means. So, I am here to share the learnings in this post as per my...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/what-is-iam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/what-is-iam/</guid>
        
        <category>iam</category>
        
        <category>architecture</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>cloud</category>
        
        <category>authentication</category>
        
        <category>authorization</category>
        
        
        <category>IAM</category>
        
        <category>Authentication</category>
        
        <category>Authorization</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Structure a React Native App</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Heads up! The structure proposed in this post is not official, it just worked nicely for me and hopefully, it will help someone else on this earth. 🙂&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here we are, writing my first post around React Native after successfully launching an app in the App Store. Not at all showing off. It was a Team effort.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But it really gave me insight with respect to “How to work around mobile apps” after being in web stack for so long. Fantastic change and am really in love with “React Native”. 🤩&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This post is specifically about how to...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/structure-react-native-project-copy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/structure-react-native-project-copy/</guid>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>architecture</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
        <category>react-native</category>
        
        <category>react</category>
        
        <category>structure</category>
        
        
        <category>Performance</category>
        
        <category>Javascript</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Time complexity - Big O Notations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have gotten an interest in algorithms, the first one I chose to understand deeply is how sorting algorithms work and their time complexity. However, this post is not to explain sorting algorithms, instead, we will take a step back and understand time complexity [Big O Notation] in the simplest way possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;before-we-go-any-further-lets-understand-what-is-an-algorithm&quot;&gt;Before we go any further, let’s understand what is an Algorithm:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;An Algorithm is a step by step instruction, telling a program to execute in a certain way to solve a particular problem. And it’s pretty obvious, that when we run a program in any language,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/time-complexity-notations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/time-complexity-notations/</guid>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>Performance</category>
        
        <category>Javascript</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating your own React Boilerplate - For Beginners</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, It’s been a while working on React, still learning and it feels pretty awesome. We all understand how important it is to interpret the basic concepts before we set our path to work with any framework or library.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Usually what happens, even as a beginner we tend to jump on things without understanding how it works, to see the practical usage, fancy stuff etc and hey &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;You are not alone!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But sometimes, it’s good to come back on time and try to understand the underlying pieces. There are tons of boilerplates available which are really helpful to kickstart...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/creating-own-react-boilerplate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/creating-own-react-boilerplate/</guid>
        
        <category>react</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>frontend</category>
        
        
        <category>React</category>
        
        <category>Frontend</category>
        
        <category>Javascript</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cool things you can do with Sass - Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Sass for like past two years and now I’m a huge fan. Even though we were doing pretty much alright with writing CSS but it never gave us that kind of flexibility that Sass provides like one of the things could be managing the complexity in stylesheets as our apps get more and more substantial. Anyways, Enough about my experience already as today we have got a bunch of cool things to cover!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-sass&quot;&gt;What is Sass?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s a CSS preprocessor, that’s what you will get if you start googling and its true but hold that...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/cool-things-you-can-do-with-sass-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/cool-things-you-can-do-with-sass-part-1/</guid>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
        <category>sass</category>
        
        <category>scss</category>
        
        
        <category>Drupal</category>
        
        <category>CSS</category>
        
        <category>Frontend</category>
        
        <category>Scss</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emboss your footprints in the Drupal Sand - Drupal Camp Goa 2018, Call for sessions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to bring you the most exciting event of this year &lt;strong&gt;Drupal Camp Goa 2018!&lt;/strong&gt; You would be ecstatic to be a part of something really big that’s happening in India’s most sought-after destination, Goa. It’s a shoutout for all of you who love developing and would like to extend their immense support to the web’s leading content management system (CMS), Drupal!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2018-01-26-drupal-camp-goa-2018-call-for-sessions/drupal-camp-goa-2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drupal Camp Goa 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-drupalers-have-all-the-fun&quot;&gt;Why should Drupalers have all the fun!&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;This time it is not just Drupal, we are exploring beyond it. Join us to share your knowledge on topics like...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/drupal-camp-goa-2018-call-for-sessions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/drupal-camp-goa-2018-call-for-sessions/</guid>
        
        <category>drupal camp</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Drupal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Must have custom drush commands in every Drupal project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am working on a project where we use Drush commands a lot …. seriously like A LOT.. That said, while working on the project, I found few drush commands which come quite handy in our day to day operations. We use these commands mostly with deploy hooks and also while working locally.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Everyone uses Drush commands which are kinda in daily use while working on Drupal and we just can’t imagine our life without it in terms of increasing our productivity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We want to be more and more productive right? Yes, we do. :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-bit-about-drush&quot;&gt;A little bit about...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/must-have-drush-commands-in-drupal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/must-have-drush-commands-in-drupal/</guid>
        
        <category>drush</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Drush</category>
        
        <category>Drupal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time to level up Code Reviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being part of a Code review process is very important for us and trust me we take it very seriously. This is required not just for the team but for an individual learning as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Code reviews are very crucial for knowledge transfer and to avoid making small/common mistakes and of course maintaining best practices throughout the dev team. So Let’s take my team for example: we are around 11 developers in the team, all producing code which needs to be reviewed. So basically yeah that’s a whole lot of code!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;why-its-important&quot;&gt;Why It’s Important?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pushing code to production is...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/time-to-level-up-code-reviews/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/time-to-level-up-code-reviews/</guid>
        
        <category>code quality</category>
        
        <category>coding standards</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Coding Practices</category>
        
        <category>Drupal</category>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping It Clean: Coding Standards That Matter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A year back, I was working on a project that taught me how to keep my code clean, modular, reusable, and all those terms that seem fancy, but are actually good for you in the long run. Interesting? Yeah a bit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But what did I do after getting into those practices?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I made mistakes. Believe me, a lot of them. But with every mistake, I learnt a lot of stuff that I had never considered before. It helped me in my thinking process, on how we should build things, what steps we need to consider when we are developing/extending a...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/coding-standards-that-matter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/coding-standards-that-matter/</guid>
        
        <category>code quality</category>
        
        <category>coding standards</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Coding Practices</category>
        
        <category>Drupal</category>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Docker Compose Work with Drupal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My last post talked about &lt;a href=&quot;/docker-microcontainers-for-faster-workflows/&quot;&gt;how Docker microcontainers speed up the software development workflow&lt;/a&gt;. Now it’s time to dive into how all this applies to Drupal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I created a collection of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lhuria94/docker-drupal-lamp&quot;&gt;Docker configuration files&lt;/a&gt; and scripts to make it easy to run Drupal. If you want to try it out, follow the steps in the README file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The repository is designed using the microcontainers concept, so that each Drupal site will end up with 3 containers of it’s own (Apache, MySQL and Drush containers), which are linked together, to run our application. If you want to serve a...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 03:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/making-docker-compose-work-with-drupal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/making-docker-compose-work-with-drupal/</guid>
        
        <category>continuous integration</category>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Continuous Integration</category>
        
        <category>Productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Docker: A Microcontainer for Faster Software Workflows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker, a container-based technology which I just came across, is great for setting up environments. It was first introduced to the world by Solomon Hykes, founder and CEO of dotCloud at Python Developers Conference in Santa Clara, California, in March 2013. The project was quickly open-sourced and made available on GitHub, where anyone can download and contribute to it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;containers-vs-virtual-machines&quot;&gt;Containers vs. Virtual Machines&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;You might be wondering, “What is the difference between Containers (like Docker) and Virtual Machines”?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Well, virtual machines (VM) work by creating a virtual copy of a computer’s hardware, and running a full operating-system on that...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 07:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/docker-microcontainers-for-faster-workflows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/docker-microcontainers-for-faster-workflows/</guid>
        
        <category>continuous integration</category>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Continuous Integration</category>
        
        <category>Productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bigpipe Caching: Making Web 2x Faster</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone loves a fast website. It’s one of the critical goals for every web developer to build a site that’s twice as fast than a previous one. And ‘BigPiping’ a website makes it super fast. BigPipe is a fundamental redesign of the dynamic web page serving system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Typically, 80-90% of the loading time is spent on front end which is very huge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A few important metrics to observe are:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Time To First Byte (TTBF): Time taken between requesting html page and starting to receive the first byte of response. In this time, the client and the browser can’t do...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 05:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lhuria94.github.io/bigpipe-caching-making-webx-faster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lhuria94.github.io/bigpipe-caching-making-webx-faster/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        <category>drupal</category>
        
        <category>drupal 8</category>
        
        <category>planet drupal</category>
        
        
        <category>Performance</category>
        
        <category>Drupal 8</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
